# MUHAMMAD SHOAIB ARSHAD

#### **BS ELECTRICAL ENGINEER**



**Personal Details:** 

**Date of Birth:** 23/10/1994

Home Address:
House No 80, ABlock Kayaban-eAmin Defense Road
Lahore

Email: Business.shoaib@o utlook.com

Contact # +92-300-0768561 +92-323-7517300

**Marital Status:** Single

CNIC #:

Nationality: Pakistani

**Religion:** ISLAM

## PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Power Professional with BSEE with 2 year of diversified professional experience. My area of expertise and interest include Project Management, Portfolio Management, Refurbishment, Risk Management, O&M of Power Plants and Maintenance. Seeking a challenging and growth oriented position with professionally managed the organization, where I can utilize my skills and support the organization to achieve its corporate goals more effectively within the stipulated time, as a team player or on own initiative.

## **EDUCATION & QUALIFICATION**

BSc. ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING
Institute of Electrical Engineering and
Technology, University of Lahore (LHR)



**Cgpa 2.85/4.00** 2013-2017

Technology, University of Lahore (LHR) LAHO

**F. Sc. PRE-ENGG** Punjab Group of Colleges, Lahore



**Grade A** 2011-2013

2009-2011

S.S.C. Science Grade A Science Higher Secondary School, Faqir Wali Bahawalnagar

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

• Certificate In INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY Approved By



Skill Development Council Islamabad

• Certificate In English Communication Skills, Government College



University(GCU) Lahore

• Event Management and Venue Operator from Lahore International



Expo Centre Lahore.

## PROCESS REPORT/FINAL YEAR PROJECT

(CANAL PROFILING: A FRAMEWORK OF MONITORING WATER AND SILTATION LEVEL OF DISTRIBUTORY CANAL USING GSM MODULE| 2016-2017

- o Hardware design and simulation work using of Arduino board and GSM module
- o Implementation of Hardware device at Lahore Distributary Canal with the collaboration of LUMS
- Research Paper Work on new technology of Irrigation Canal System using GSM module

# MUHAMMAD SHOAIB ARSHAD

#### **BS ELECTRICAL ENGINEER**

## **INTERNSHIPS**



## **Descon Engineering, Lahore:**

4 Weeks as a Trainee Engineer, 2017

- Characteristics of transmitter technology used in boiler for measuring, monitoring and controlling.
- Areas of expertise included electrical power distribution.
- Variable frequency drive (VFD).
- Detailed study about Process Control Elements.
- Designed and installed multi-level control system using PLC has and relay logic.
- Learned the process and procedures of fire tube boiler.



### Nishat Emporium under Guarantee Engineers Pvt Ltd

June-July2016

- Collect the Site Statistical data from the project site.
- Summarized the overall data and evaluate to perform analysis.
- Conduct Inspections.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Fazl-E-Rasheed & Co LLC, Lahore



(Jan 2018 to Jun 2018)

#### **RESPONSIBILITIES**

- I was working as Technical Engineer (Batteries & Fork lifters Division)
- I have visited different companies like PTCL, Zong, Big Bird Foods Plant, Packages Limited, Engro Foods Sahiwal, Style Textile, Interloop, Nestle Pakistan, Tetra Pak, ICI Pakistan Ltd, IFL and Allied Engineering.
- I was leading the "Regeneration process" of Open Lead Acid/Traction & Dry Gel Batteries up to DC 80V/1000Ah.
- Head of the Lab, which was converting Low backup time Batteries into Refurbished/New Batteries.
- Collect the Daily Basis Statistical Data of All operated Fork lifer Machines at different Sites.
- Coordination with all Pakistan Sites



## **Lahore International Expo Centre (Social Media Marketing)**

(Jan 2017 – Dec 2017)

#### **RESPONSIBILITIES**

- Development of brand Events awareness and online reputation
- Content Management.
- Create a regular Publishing schedule.
- Implement a Content editorial calendar to manage content and plan specific, timely Marketing campaigns.
- Promote Content through social advertising.

# MUHAMMAD SHOAIB ARSHAD

#### **BS ELECTRICAL ENGINEER**

#### **INTEREST:**

Internet Surfing Reading Newspaper Cricket Travelling

#### LANGUAGES:

English Urdu Punjabi Turkish

# MICROSOFT SKILLS:

Microsoft Word Microsoft Excel Microsoft Power Point

### **PROJECTS:**

# SINGLE AND THREE PHASE INVERTER | POWER ELECTRONICS | JAN 2016

- o Single and Three Phase power circuit Designing and Simulation Work.
- Using of Pulse Width Modulation (PWM) with high harmonic distortion having Conversion efficiency is 90-95%.

#### DESIGNING AND SIMULATION OF TRANSFORMER – SEP 2015

- o Designing and Simulation work of Current Transformer.
- o Working on the Transformer Faults: Ground Faults, phase to phase faults etc.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Attended Seminar on World Environment Day
- Manage 50+ National and International Events at Expo Centre Lahore
- Member of the Extra Curricular Activities Group at the School
- Remained College Representative during College
- Participated with distinction in all the guiz contests at the School
- Permanent Member of Pakistan Engineering Congress (PEC)
- Winner of Cricket, Table Tennis & Volley Ball tournament at Pak Turk University Hostel, Lahore.

## **KEY COMPETENCES**

- Conduct Toolbox Talks and Safety Committee meetings
- Tremendous Ability for "People Management"
- Able to communicate in English & Urdu
- Able to work in team, can lead and co-ordinate
- Seeks new responsibilities irrespective of reward and recognition
- Able to work under stress, task and time oriented
- Self-motivated dynamic and Strong resolution
- Excellent written and oral communication skills
- Microsoft Office tools: MS Word, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint
- Operating System: Microsoft Windows XP, Windows 7, Windows 8.

## **PROFESSIONAL TRAININGS & COURSES**

- Industrial Training Certification
- Presentation Skills
- Developing Leadership Skills
- Business Communication Skills
- Team Building
- Time Management
- Cost Control for Projects
- Microsoft Excel

#### **REFERENCE**

References will be furnished on demand.